# Olin Kirkland

Brühler Landstraße 2, 50997 Köln, Germany plakat@live.com; +49 162 372 0898 https://www.olinkirk.land

# **SUMMARY**

I am an adaptable programmer and UI developer with a passion for making games and producing high quality OOP code. My professional experience includes core front-end development for large scale applications, game development, and application design. In my free time, I work on personal game-related projects with an emphasis in user interface design and procedural generation.

## **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: ActionScript 3 + Apache Flex, Haxe + OpenFl, Javascript, C#
- IDEs/Software: IntelliJ IDEA, HaxeDevelop, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Adobe Animate
- UI and application design: Paper prototyping, storyboards, moodboards
- Soft skills: Effective communicator, team player, problem solver
- Communication: Native English and German

#### **EDUCATION**

## George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, United States

Completed coursework towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science September 2011 – June 2013

## Oakton High School, Fairfax, VA, United States

Graduated with Advanced Placement September 2007 – June 2011

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

References to Adobe Air/Adobe Flash imply the language Actionscript 3

# BRIGHT FUTURE GMBH., Cologne, NRW, Germany

Game Developer, April 2020 – Present

- Work closely with other programmers and designers to develop and maintain a massively multiplayer browser game
- Debug and refactor the codebase emphasizing readability and improved scalability
- Assist in the migration from ActionScript 3 to Haxe to maintain efficacy on the browser platform
- Complete code reviews and manage documentation
- Technologies: Haxe, OpenFl, Starling, Android Studio

# DALLMEIER GMBH., Regensburg, BY, Germany

Flex Developer, May 2018 – April 2020

- Worked closely with other programmers and designers to build intuitive user interfaces
- Developed various interactive modules for displaying and visualizing data in a user-friendly dashboard
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Apache Flex

## PAUL BERNHARD EXHIBIT DESIGN AND CONSULTING, Houston, TX, United States

**Interactive Developer**, September 2015 – May 2018

- Designed and developed interactive touch screen applications and media kiosks for deployment in the Wiess Energy Hall of the Houston Museum of Natural Science
- Directed the organization and implementation of museum content for custom applications
- Created maps from custom data sets using industry standard GIS tools
- Developed visualizations for data from a wide variety of formats and sources including data from RESTful APIs related to the energy sector and extensive industry data sets
- Created moodboards and storyboards for application design
- Managed and carried out the deployment of applications to their intended hardware
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Adobe Flex, C#, Unity, HTML, Javascript, Adobe Flash, Arduino

## RENAISSANCE CHILD, Arlington, VA, United States

Technology Lead and Camp Instructor, April 2015 – September 2015

- Researched and purchased required hardware and software, provided on-site tech support
- Created lesson plans and activities relating to subjects including mechanical engineering, stop-motion, programming, and robotics
- Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

#### ODESK.COM

Freelance Interactive Media Developer, June 2013 – April 2015

- Consulted with clients to determine design and functionality of software
- Developed and implemented Flash and Adobe Air applications
- Created small graphics like logos or profile pictures
- Maintained an organized archive of versions and products

## GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY, Fairfax, VA, United States

Flash Developer, January 2012 – May 2013

- Created a variety of Flash apps that were hosted on the University website (dynamic banners, etc.)
- Developed interactive university floor plan and virtual tour apps
- Technologies: Adobe Flash